In the world of business and in marketing,
在商业分析领域
we often talk a lot about processes.
我们经常会提到各种流程
We do this because processes help us work efficiently and effectively.
这是因为流程能帮助我们更高效地工作
They're also a great foundation when you're
如果你刚开始接触这个领域 流程也可以帮助你更容易地开始
starting out because it gives you something to work through.
因为你只要遵循流程就可以了
It helps you practice and repeat these behaviors
你可以先练习 不断重复流程
that then allow you to understand why you're doing certain things.
然后再理解为什么要做这些事情
Whatever we're trying to do with our data,
无论我们想对数据做何种处理
the process is always the same.
流程是一样的
Measure, analyze, and improve.
Measure (评估) &gt; analyze (分析) &gt; improve (优化)
The first step is to measure.
第一步是评估
Now, we know that we have all of this data to pick from.
我们知道有很多数据需要挑选出来
Now, it's actually relatively cheap and easy to simply collect all of the data you can.
其实现在要收集所有的数据也是相对简单和容易的
However, that can cause some problems.
但是 这会引起一些问题
First of all, simply collecting all of the data you can could
首先 不管三七二十一 就先收集所有的数据
create a problem by which you're just chasing after all of these sources.
会让你的工作重心放在定位和使用所有的数据工具上面
Remember, you simply want to be using the tools that matter
记住 你应该仅仅使用那些对你来说有用的工具
and then let those tools collect all the data that they can.
然后让这些工具去收集相关的所有信息
When it comes time to use that data though,
选择使用哪些数据时
it's important to be selective.
也要谨慎选择
Otherwise, it'll be like drinking from a fire hose.
否则就像是大海捞针
When it comes to measure,
评估的时候
we're going to focus on these objectives.
我们应该特别关注我们的目标
Remember, we take our objectives.
根据目标来评估
We look through that lens to determine what we're measuring.
透过目标来决定评估哪些数据
Now, once we've measured all of this data and we've collected these metrics,
一旦收集了数据和确定了指标
it's time to analyze it.
我们就可以开始分析
So we take the data, we inspect it,
拿到数据 检查数据
and we start developing insights that allow us to take action.
然后我们就能开始分析 取得洞察
Analyzing data is similar to being a detective.
分析数据有点像做侦探
Now, we're going to talk a lot about analyzing data later on and we'll
后续我们会详细地讲述数据分析
really go into depth about how to think through your analysis.
以及如何进行数据分析思考
After we've done the analyzing, we improve.
分析的下一步就是优化
Everything that we do has to be actionable,
我们所做的一切都是为了产出一个可执行的方案
you're going to hear me repeat this often.
在后续课程里 我会不断重复这个观点
You need to figure out what you're really doing with this data.
你需要思考如何利用这些数据
Simply collecting it and looking at it isn't good
仅收集和分析数据是不够的
enough and then reporting on it still isn't good enough.
甚至汇报这些数据洞察都是不够的
You need to make sure that the information that you're sharing has action behind it.
你应该确保这些信息被分享后 能有一个可执行的方案
What is the goal of looking at this information?
这些信息的目标是什么？
What decision are you going to make based off of it?
基于这些信息 你要采取什么决策？
From there, you simply repeat this process.
我们可以不断重复上述过程
Every time you take on a new initiative,
每次有新项目的时候
whenever you start a new marketing campaign,
比如新的市场活动
think first about what needs to be measured,
先想想需要评估哪些数据
then analyze it, and then improve it.
然后分析 最后优化
As we spend more time together digging into real-world scenarios,
接下来我们会花很多时间在真实的业务场景上
always pay attention to the steps we take.
请记住这些步骤
Regardless of the project,
不管项目具体如何 00:02:30,185 --&gt; 00:00:00,000 流程都是 评估 分析 优化